John N. Rowe III papers, Inclusive: 1510-1989, undated, Bulk: 1830-1880
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Spanish Documents, 1
  - de la Garza, Bernardino, Valle de Santa Rosa-sells half of Ranch Senora (Santa Ana), 1825 March 19 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - de la Garza, Bernardino, Valle de Santa Rosa-Land title to Juan Jose Zamora, 1825 June 6 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - de la Garza, Bernardino, Valle de Santa Rosa, Appointment of Joaquin Minguiz and Simon de la Garza, 1826 June 6 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - de la Rosa, Simon, Alcalde de Santa Rosa, Jose Francisco Madero, 1826 January 22 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - de Landazuri, Estanislao-Superintendent of the Royal Coffers, De Croix (Lima, Peru), 1788 October 8 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - de Linares, Benito Antonio, Maria Gregoria Gil de los Rios, Manuel Joseph (Mathis Rodriguez Flores), 1759 May 11-12, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - de Madrid, Jose Fernandez, 1836 October 15 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - de Santa Anna, Antonio Lopez, 1822 October 15 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - de Zavala, Pedro, 1821 December 4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - del Pont, Ventura Miguel Marco, Francisco Antonio de los Ayala, 1809 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Del Rey, Felix Maria Calleja, 1813 December 23 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Echavaria, Padilla, Tres Palacios, 1758 April 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Elquezabal, Juan Jose, 1834 August 30 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Estrada, Gutierrez, Provisional President of the Mexican United States, 1835 May 23 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Flores, Jose Maria, 1844 November 11 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Flores, Refujio, Coahuila, Texas-to Mayor Bernardino de la Garza, 1825 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Guerrero, C. Vicente, 1829 February 9 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Inclan, Colonel Ignacio, 1844 January 5 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Inclan, Colonel Ignacio, 1844 April 1 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Inclan, Colonel Ignacio, Valentin, Canalizo, 1844 April 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Jiminez, Jose Maria, 1836 January 3 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - [illegible], Jose Antonio-Puebla, 1852 April 17 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Liano, Pedro Manuel, Joseph [illegible], 1753 February 4 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Madero, J. Francisco, 1831 February 23 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Madrid, Luis-President, 1852 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Manillo, J. Estevan, Santa Rosa-Monclova, 1836 January (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Manillo, J. Estevan, Santa Rosa-Monclova, 1836 February (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Manillo, J. Estevan, Santa Rosa-Monclova, 1836 March (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Manillo, J. Estevan, Santa Rosa-Monclova, 1836 April (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Manillo, J. Estevan, Santa Rosa-Monclova, 1836 May (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Mendinueta, Pedro, 1757 September 20 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Mexia, Jose Antonio, Mexico-to David Burnet, 1836 April 28 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Mexico, Jose Antonio, Mexico-to David Burnet, 1836 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Mexias y Reynoso, Gasper, 1815 December 2 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Mexias y Reynoso, Gasper, 1806-1807 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Musquiz, Ramon, 1833 March 23 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Navarro, Angel, 1835 July 30 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Palacio, Mariano Riva-to municipal leaders in Estado de Mexico, 1850 April 19 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Palacio, Vicente Riva-Mexican Republic, 1877 November 24 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Quintanar, Luis-free state of Xalisco, 1823 October 11 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Raymond, Charles, 1890 May 20 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Rea, General Joaquin, “Heroic People of Puebla”, 1847 August 25 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Rincon, Colonel Manuel, 1845 January 22 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Rincon, Colonel Manuel, 1845 March 31 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Rojo, Mario, Valle del Rio-Cuernavaca, to Manuel Lozano, 1846 February 22 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Romero, Jesus R., 1865 July 26 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Ruey, Guis, 1834-1835 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Sterne, Adolphus, 1833 July 13 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Sterne, Adolphus, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Torres y Catano, C. Manuel-to habitants of Estado de Mexico, 1853 June 11 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Unidentified, Georgio Solano (Lima), 1735 March 29 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - unidentified, discusses Socorros Mine (Lima), 1735 October 16 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Unidentified, 1784 June 12 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Unidentified, 1784 July 7 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Unidentified, Manuel [illegible] Juan [illegible], 1808 July 25 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Velasquez, Tizan, Cuernavaca, Mexico, 1846 February 21 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Villegas, Pedro Rodriguez, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Villegas, Santiago-Zacatecas, 1836 December 13 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Williams, Samuel, Vicente Aldrate, 1834 June 7 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Zambrano, Juan-Military Budget Information, Mexico, 1857 August 31 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Zamora, Victoriano-Zacatecas, 1856 June 19 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Instructions: Streeter: de Veramendi, Juan Martin, City of Leona Vicario, to Government Officials, 1833 February 4 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Marco, Ventura Miguel, Antonio Bazo y Berry (Cadiz, Spain), 1810 May 4 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - de ‘Chopitea’, Pedro Nicolas (Santiago, Chile), 1802 May 2 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - del Pont, Ventura Miguel Marco, Manuel de Cubas, 1802 June 5 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Municipal Documents: San Luis Potisi, Mexico, 1849-1852 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Governor and President of the Congress of the Free State of Mexico, 1834 August 27 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Official Newspaper of the Government of Nuevo Leon, Mexico (Daniel Webster), 1843 November 30 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Palacio, Miguel, provisional Governor of the Free State of Veracruz, 1849 October 31 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper of the State of Tamoulipas, Mexico, 1849 November 21 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - : Notification from General of Havana, 1822 February 6 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Spanish and English Document (English document mentions Samuel Murphy), 1835 October 10 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Murphy, Samuel—regarding land, 1834-1835 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - Austin, Henry (Henrique), 1830 February 24 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - Bega, Thomas, Antonio de la Garza, 1834 May 14 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - de Salazar, Don Juan, Mexico City—Declaration, 1789 July 11 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 16)
  - de la Torre, Marcos and Carranza, to Anontio de la Bodega (List), 1778 November 13 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 17)
  - Filisola, General, 1829 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 18)
  - Pavon, Jose Maria—Puebla, 1851 December 10 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 19)
  - Cantu, Vicente, James Hewetson, 1834 June 23 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 20)
  - de Ecay y Mazquiz, Joseph Joaquin, et al. (Real Presidio de Santa Rosa Madrid del Sacramento — Coahuila), 1762 January 2 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 21)
  - de la Garza, Bernadino, Valle de Santa Rosa—Maria Guerra sells land to Margarito Perez, 1825 July 18 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 22)
  - de la Garza, Bernadino, Valle de Santa Rosa—Rafael Madrazo sells land to Juan Arredondo, 1825 August 2 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 23)
  - Don Fernando VII—to the Spanish people and Spaniards in the Americas, undated (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 24)
  - Illegible Spanish Document, Coahuila y Texas, 1837 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 25)
  - Rincon, Don Manuel—Coronel, 1822 June 15 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 26)
  - Rincon, El Ciudadano Manuel, 1845 June 9 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 27)
  - List of Rights and Fees Charged to Different Groups for Services by the Diocese, undated (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - 9th Constitutional Congress of the State of Puebla, Puebla Zaragoza, to Governor Rosendo Marquez, 1887 September 13 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - “Me, the KingEL”, 1820 April 17 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - 7th Constitutional Congress of the State L. and S. of Puebla Zaragoza, to Governor Juan N. Mendez, 1884 September 15 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - El Censor de Veracruz, Mexico, To the Audience, 1838 April 18 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - De Apodaca y Eliza, Juan Ruiz, 1819 March 17 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Calleja, Felix, 1813 September 10 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified, Mariano Arista, 1849 October 26 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified: List of Political Functionaries, undated (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Junta de Fomento y Administrativa de Mineria, Miguel Hierro, 1846 January 13 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Junta de Fomento y Administrativa de Mineria, 1845 February (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Official Newspaper of the City of San Luis Potosi (Santa Ana, President Jackson), 1837 January 20 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Martinez, Antonio Joaquin Perez, Jose Francisco Compomanes, 1831 March 21 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - Official Register, Government of the Mexican United States, 1831 March 5 (Box 48 OVZ, Folder 14)
- Early Texas Documents, 1801-1989, undated; 2
  The Early Texas Documents series contains general correspondence, legal documents such as land grants and titles, wills, marriage licenses, court documents and legal representation documents. It also contains financial documents such as treasury warrants, bonds, inventories and numerous pieces of currency from the Republic of Texas as well as the Civil War period. Rounding out this series are documents in German, French and Latin, flyers, sheet music, invitations, tickets, circulars, and publications.
  - Correspondence, 1828-1989, undated; 1
    The correspondence subseries consists of general correspondence with no set theme or groupings. Of particular note is one letter to General S.F. Austin, Branch F. Archer and William H. Wharton from October 16, 1835, relating that "Bexar has fallen!"
    - Correspondence: Adkerson, M.B., 1874 June 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Andujar, Betty, Debbie Freeman “Agreement to speak on 1975 April 5”, 1975 January 29 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Anonymous: Concerning Sam Houston’s Communications About the Battle of Horse Shoe, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Austin, Gen. S.F., Branch F. Archer, William H. Wharton, D.C. Barrett, R.R. Royals, James Powers “Bexar has fallen!!”, 1835 December 15 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Ballinger, William P to William H. Macfarland, 1860 November 16 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Belcher, Galitzen, 1832 April 14 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Birge, H.A., Maj. S. Hart, 1864 December 13 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Blair, William C., 1843 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Blake, Hon. Amos J., H.G. Damon, Sabine Land & Mining Company, 1890 August 13 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Bryan W.J., undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Bullard, C.A., 1849 July 2 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Burnet, David G., Bailey Hardiman, 1836 March 21 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Burnet, David G., 1842 August 22 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Busby, Jacob J., W.P. Herring, O.E. Rhodes, Charles Bullock, Jennings, J. Shackelford “Directions for shipping of cotton and pork", 1854 November 1 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Butler, George, Joseph H. Ward “Notice that shipment of cotton has arrived”, 1839 April 10 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Cabell, W.L. “Envelope”, 18[ ] April 28 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Cabot, Godfrey L., Honorable Hatton W. Summers “Invitation to National Aeronautic Association Dinner”, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Chastain, Morgan, P.H. Oliver, 1840 August 21 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Coryelle, Lewis S., 1844 March 1 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Crane, R.C., Dan Moody, 1929 July 3 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Crane, W.C., [illegible ] February 8 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Crosby, L., D. Cordova, McGaffey, Haxnie, Rowe “acknowledgement that request for patents has been delayed”, 1847 March 30 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Danger field, William Henry, Henderson “Letter requesting confirmation of arrival of ship”, 1840 January 14 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: De Young, Doctor [William M.] Carper, 1857 June 30 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: Diggs, George P., John W. Moody, 1834 October 22 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: Dimmitt, Philip (Goliad), 1835 November 18 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: Dimmit, Philip, La. Vaca, Thomas Powel, 1834 July 17 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Dimmitt P., 1838 January (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: Durst, John M., John Davis, John Saxton, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Envelope, 1989 March 3 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Envelope, Brooks, Josie L., 1894 August 12 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Envelope from Early Texas, Circa 1870s-1890s (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Envelope form Mrs. Frank Hodge to The Numismatic Bank, Fort Worth, Texas, circa 1916-1917 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Envelope from Jacob Routh, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Envelope from Texas, 1901, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: Farish, Oscar, 1866 October (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Floyd, John B., John Cochrane, Guy M. Bryan (Galveston Harbor), 1859 January 13 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Gardiner, J.B., M. Nichols, 1844 September 25 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Gentry, G.W., T.E. Thomas, 1878 December 21 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: Gildersleeve, Phillip, 1847 April 18 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Gillespie County Texas Centennial Memorial (1846-47) Mailout (Fredericksburg), 1936 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence: Gillett, E.P., Samuel Joanah Thomas, John S. Roberts “Letter informing of latest business transactions”, 1839 April 29 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Gillett, E.P., J.D. Thomas, Samuel Joanah Thomas “Acknowledgement of goods received”, 1838 June 1 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: Gillett, E.P., H. Keller, N.B. Dart, Samuel Joanah Thomas, W. Caldwell “Letter updating current business situation”, 1838 July 19 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Gillett, E.P., Samuel Joanah Thomas “Letter detailing latest business ventures”, 1839 July 9 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence: Gillett, E.P., Samuel Joanah Thomas “Letter explaining latest business venture”, 1838 July 22-September 28 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence: Goeth, C.A., 1893-1934 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence: Goodwin, John H., Thomas Matly, Luke Anson, 1836 August 1 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence: Gramann, H.C., J.W. Vince, 1883 June 13 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence: Green, Duff, 1844 February 2 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence: Guntz, S., 1850 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence: Hall, Edward, Layton & Company, 1839 April 12 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence: Harris, Mrs. Jacob Ruth (Routh?), 1846 September 7 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence: Harris, R.A., 1859 February 22 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence: Harris, R.A., 1859 April 4 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence: Harris, R.A., Miss [M.J.], 1857 June 3 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence: Harrison, William, Phoebe Pane Harrison, 1853 January 23 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence: Haviland, James E., 1842 February 1 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence: Hersey, David, 1850 September 28 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence: Honold, C., Charles L. Taylor, Johann Eberhard Ruoff, William West, Elisabeth Ruoff,Anna Maria Diehl, F. Honold, Johann Seremias Ruoff, Clara Serbold Sherand “Letter Requesting Documents to Process Power of Attorney”, 1854 September 20 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence: Houston, Sam, 1849 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Howard, C., Bridges, J. Robertson, A.B. Flewry, J.S.H. Bartlett, J.S. Bartlett, J. Adam, Andrews, Wallace, Royall, Mills, Chambers, Samuel H. Williams, Fisher “Request for goods to sell in Texas”, 1835 July 16 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Howe, John, William J. Gourlay, 1846 June 13 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Howell, Martha E., Joseph Routh, 1847 July 25 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Hubbard, James B., Ernest Vickers, 1922 August 9, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Jones, John Rice, Jr., John Wooldridge, 1845 October 6 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Kohoe, James, William C. Byrne, 1848 April 6 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Loewenstern, Hugo H., Preston Smith, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Maynard & Shaw, Frederick W. Mueller, 1846 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: McCaleb, Walter F. Sr., 1962-1966, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: McDowell, Mills, Johnston & Dewberry, 1851 October 30 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: McEnery, Agnes: “Pithy Anecdotes of Sam Houston”, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: McRae, Colin T., William H. Jack (Exhibit K), 1847 June 29 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Miller, L.K., Weaver & Simonds, 1869 April 20 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Moore, D.E., 1861 September 21 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Newell, Stewart, Theodore Gillies, 1846 December 22 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Oliver, P.H., Henry Atkinson, Pete Oliver “Letter explaining current events involving the author”, 1840 August 12 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Plummer, Samuel A., 1839 May 14 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Rany, J.E., Samuel G Matthews, J.W. Cosby, Markus Walker, Rutherford, Anna Rany, J. Davis, Bentomplcins “Letter requesting reply to previous letters” (Folder 79)
    - Correspondence: 1859 November 24, 10; 19 (Folder 80)
    - Correspondence: Richard/David [Land in Huut Co.], 1869 May (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Ross, Shapley P., 1899 April 11 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Routh, Jacob, W.A. Routh, 1852 October (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Rusk, Thomas-Signed Daguerreotype, 1837 May 20 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: Savage, H., Henry Thilbaum, 1834 March 24 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: S. Schutz & Bro., John Twohig, 1873 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: Selegson, Michael, Joseph Pascovitch, 1846 February 10 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: Shaw, James R., Edward Hall, 1851 June 11 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Simms, Coleman F., Austin, Clapp “Request to ship cotton to market”, 1846 July 27 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: Sloan, L.T., 1903 April 27 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Sprague, Francis C., Sam P. Crain, 1845 September 23 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Stark, John T., undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Taylor, Job, 1851 February 6 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Teal, H. Edward Teal, 1836 September 2 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Thomas, Benjamin, 1835 October (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Thurs, Simeon, W.P. Herring, Johnathan C. Thurs, Nathaniel Hamlins “Directions for shipping cotton and order for goods”, 1854 October 30 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: Tower, John, Debbie Freeman “Letter Declining Invitation to trans-American international conference”, 1974 December 3 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Walker, Robert J. N.C. Raymond, Senator Richard Bache, 1848 March 18 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Ward, Thomas W. and A.F. James, unsafe mail system, 1846 November (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: Watkinson, James H., William Hendley & Company, 1847 January 6 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Western Land Corporation, Houston, Texas, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence: White, M.M., O.H. Cross, 1936 March 23 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Whitmarsh & Co., Cleveland, 1845 October 22 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: Williams, Mrs. Alice, W.A. Hinnant, 1914 January (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Williams, John C., 1837 December 5 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence: Wilson, Zeshi “Letter to Zeshi Wilson”, 1873 June 14 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence: Wright, Jim, Debbie Freeman “letter declining invitation to speak”, 1975 January 3 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence: Routh, Jacob, Joseph [illegible], 1850 August 18 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: Gillett, E. P., Samuel Joanah Thomas, John S. Roberts, 1839 April 29 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Brauns, F. L., Charles L. Taylor, Mrs. Serne, Mrs. Taylor, 1853 March 30 (Box 46 OVZ, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Brent, John H. P., 1837 June 3 (Box 47 OVZ, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: “A Letter from Judge MorrisEL”, undated (Box 49 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Legal, 1801-1924, undated; 2
    The legal subseries is the largest of the Early Texas Documents and consists of materials covering land grants, land titles, wills, marriages, court documents, and documents pertaining to legal representation. In some cases, there are more than one document for a particular person, but most are stand alone items. Rare signatures such as Moses Austin, Stephen F. Austin, and Sam Houston can be found in this subseries.
    - Legal: 1846 November 7 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Legal: Adair, Joseph and Isaac Adair, 1850 August (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Legal: Adsit, Charles S., Nash Banton, 1855 July (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Legal: Adsit, George A., 1853 November 5 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Legal: Adsit, George W., 1853 September (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Legal: Albert Gallatin (Sale of)—Jacob M. Hunter, Charles Powell, Julius H. Sterrett, William Wade, Jr., 1841 December 17 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Legal: Alden, J. M., undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Legal: Alexander, Martin, R. D. Heck, William Hunt, 1857 August (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Legal: Alexander, Oscar T. and John Falls, 1839 November (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Legal: Allen, Amos, Phineas G. Merritt, Curtis Merritt, 1849 November 13 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Legal: Alley, Abraham, 1840 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Legal: Andrews, Edmund, E. A. Rhodes, John H. Benmett, John S. Jones, Estate of John Seinardy, 1844 March 2 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Legal: Andrews, Wright S. and George W. Grover, 1855 May (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Legal: Anonymous, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Legal: Armstrong, George, Ephemia L. Robertson, 1850 June 18 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Legal: Armstrong, George, James W. Bryan, Euphemia L. Robertson, John W. Parker, Pauline A. B. Parker, Cecile W. Robertson, Edward C. Robertson, Asa E. B. Robertson, 1850 June 18 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Legal: Arnold, Daniel H., Francis S. Lathrop, Alexander G. Cochran, 1847 February 17 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Legal: Arnold, Daniel H., Francis L. Lathrop and Alexander G. Cochron, 1847 February (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Legal: Arnold, Daniel H., Francis L. Lathrope, Alexander G. Cockran, 1857 January 17 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Legal: Arnold, Hayden, Juan Ariola, David Rusk “Arrest Warrant for Juan Ariola”, 1838 September 28 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Legal: Arnold, Hayden, Juan Ariola, David Rusk, John Hoblett ‘Bill of Indictment for Juan Ariola”, 1838 December 20 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Legal: Arrington, William W., A. B. Fleury, Thomas Heard, Josiah R. Franklin, 1849 October 16 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Legal: Arrington, William W. A. B. Fleury, J. H. Wood, Thomas Heard, Josiah R. Franklin, 1853 April 20 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Legal: Arrington, William W., H. B. Henry, J. H. Wood, Thomas Heard, Josiah K. Franklin, B. B. Baxter, B. F. Rucker, B. E. Tarver, 1853 April 20 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Legal: Arrington, William W., A. B. Fleury, J. H. Wood, Thomas Heard, Josiah R. Franklin, 1853 April 24 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Legal: Arrington, William W., A. B. Fleury, J. H. Wood, Thomas Heard, Josiah R. Franklin, 1853 April 24 (Box 11, Folder 26)